Preliminary Inventory to the Medal Collection, 1882-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
Medal Collection, 1882-1985
XX344
22 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes (11.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Medals from many countries, relating to the two world wars, to political events in the twentieth century, and to miscellaneous subjects.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Medals.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945.
Container List
- American Red Cross (Box 1.)
- Belen, Jacques van der (CRB)
- Carrher, Mortimer (U.S. Navy medal)
- Casebolt, Kerby Quentin (France - World War I)
- Cook, John D. (Eisenhower inauguration, 1957)
- Cooper, W. A. (German medal)
- Corcoran, William W., (2 medals)
- Dunham, Mary (Edith Cavell)
- Eustis, Alvin, Mrs. (CRB)
- Fédération Interalliée des Anciens Combattants
- France - World War I (Box 2.)
- George Washington Bicentennial
- Germany - World War I. Includes a medal provided by Frank Golder with the following [translated] text: "Make the sign of the cross over yourself, Orthodox people, and call with Us the blessing of the Lord upon your free labor," 1861 February 19 (engraving: N. Kozin; model: Count F. Tolstoy)
- Great Britain - Kings and queens
- Green, Boynton (Lusitania medal)
- Harris, David (Franz Josef memorial) (Box 3.)
- Harris, David (World War I)
- Hengy, W. B., Mrs. (World War I)
- Hill, Henry G. (U.S. Selective Service)
- Hoover, Herbert (Presidential and relief work)
- Hoover, Lou Henry (Austria)
- Hoover Institution (Belgium - World War I) (Box 4.)
- Hoover Institution (Germany - World War I) (Box 5.)
- Hoover Institution (miscellaneous) (Box 6.)
- Hoover Institution (U.S. Presidents) (Box 7.)
- Hoover Institution (Belgium - World War I)
- Jones, Samuel G. (Austria - World War I)
- Jordan, David Starr (Japanese medal) (Box 8.)
- Kellogg, Vernon and Charlotte (World War I)
- Meserole, W. H. (Belgium - World War I)
- National Broadcasting Company (10th anniversary)
- Netherlands - World War II (fascist)
- Potsdam Conference, 1945
- Rodew, Nir (Russia) (Box 9.)
- Ross, Frank S. (Belgium and miscellaneous)
- Samsonow, Michael S. (White Russian medal) (Box 10.)
- Sanger, Walter N. (France - World War I)
- Sbrana, Luigi (Lusitania medal)
- Social Justice (Soldiers' and athletes' medal)
- Stevens, Charles (German communist)
- USSR Exposition, 1974
- World Foundation
- Miscellaneous
- Spalding, Keith (World War I) (Box 11-17.)
- France - Kings (Box 18.)
- Groves, Lawrence (Austria - World War I)
- U.S. - Presidents
- Cavalier, William (Britain - commemorating military and naval victories) (Box 19.)
- Commission for Relief in Belgium
- Hunt, George, Major (U.S. - American Defense Service medal)
- Miscellaneous
- Jadot, Albert (Leopold de Beer medal)
- Smith, Clarence M., Mrs. (Belgium - CRB)
- Henry Cutler Wolfe, (11 medals) (Box 20.)
- Turkish medal commemorating Kemal Ataturk, 1937
- Ion Duca commemorative medal (Box 21.)
- Ralph C. Smith (Japanese campaign medal for Manchurian campaign,1931-1934)
- Smith, Dan Throop, (14 French medals)
- Henry M. Robinson medals
  - Andrew W. Mellon medal
  - Sons of the Revolution medal
  - Unidentified medal
- Henry Cutler Wolfe (George Washington Medal of the Freedom Foundation of Valley Forge) (Box 22.)
- Henry M. Robinson medals (Box 23.)
  - Society of Colonial Wars medal
  - Centenaire de la Banque de France, 1800-1900
  - M.O. Loyal Legion - U.S.
  - Xth Olympiad, Los Angeles, 1932 (2)
  - Banque de Paris et des Pays-Bas, 50e anniversaire, 1872-1922
  - République Française, 1870 (2)
  - Unidentified medal
- Perry, Robert, Mrs., (3 medals and 6 ribbons, American and French)
- Tsarist Russian medals, (4 medals)
- Medal commemorating the sinking of the Lusitania
- Allies - World War I, (8 panels) (Box 24.)